Hiro Mas Prides himself on running an
independent Pharmacy it's the embodiment
of what I want Healthcare to be I would
like it to be more personalized he
worries new agreements in the pharmacare
sector will erode those standards we're
slowly moving towards the American model
where it's all going to be just high
volume pill factories patients who are
insured by manual life and need
specialty drugs used to be able to get
them from either bore Healthcare or lbla
owned Pharmacy es for many now lbl is
their only option manual says specialty
drugs represent less than 1% of
prescription claims in Canada they're
expensive and are used to treat
illnesses like cancer osteoporosis and
hepatitis C manual life uh has
identified that they're basically able
to get a better deal by just going to a
single uh provider that keeps costs down
for the insurer though it raises concern
concerns about choice for patients who
live in rural or remote areas they may
go to their Pharmacy that they regularly
go to and find out that they have to
switch pharmacies or go somewhere else
Manu life says the move will offer
greater convenience labl says patients
shouldn't notice a difference and they
can pick up prescriptions or have them
deliver to their home Arrangements like
these that offer a preferred Pharmacy
have become more common in Canada though
rules ban them in Quebec some experts
suggest they limit competition if
smaller Farm phes feel squeezed if
they're left out of being able to sign
these larger deals how does this affect
their business model um and how does it
make it viable for them to remain open
you're going to
have probably two big players in the
pharmacy field okay and they're going to
control the entire market and then
they're going to call the shots he and
others wonder if deals like these will
be a slippery slope Nisha Patel CBC News
Toronto